There’s nothing better than a walk in the countryside for lifting our spirits.
没什么比在乡间散步更能让人心情舒畅的了。
Connecting with nature has been proven to help our mental health.
事实证明，亲近自然有助于改善我们的心理健康。
For some, the best tonic is to stroll through a forest, but as we admire the trees that surround us, it’s worth knowing these trees are doing more than just being nice things to look at.
对有些人来说，最好的“良药”就是在林间漫步，但当我们欣赏着身边的树木时，或许值得了解的是，这些树木的作用远不止赏心悦目那么简单。
We’re already aware of the healing properties of trees – they produce oxygen and clean the air we breathe by absorbing about a quarter of all human-caused carbon dioxide emissions.
我们早已知道树木具有有益健康的功效——它们产生氧气，还能吸收人类活动排放的约四分之一的二氧化碳，净化我们呼吸的空气。
Deforestation isn’t helping with this which is why so many people want to save them.
毁林行为会破坏这一过程，这也是许多人希望保护树木的原因。
But there’s more to these impressive forms of vegetation than we might think.
但这些令人赞叹的植物，远比我们想象的要“厉害”。
Researchers have discovered evidence that proves they are actually intelligent.
研究人员已经找到证据，证明树木其实是有“智慧”的。
It’s thought that trees talk and share resources right under our feet, using a fungal network.
人们认为，树木会通过地下的真菌网络“交谈”并共享资源。
Under the ground are tree roots, and mingling among them, along with bacteria, are thousands of superfine threads of fungi, known as hyphae.
地下遍布树根，而在树根之间，除了细菌之外，还生长着成千上万条极其纤细的真菌丝，也就是菌丝。
And research has shown that they are all interconnected.
研究表明，这些菌丝相互连接成网。
They can help each other by sharing nutrients, and they can even warn of approaching threats.
树木可以通过这个网络共享养分，甚至还能预警即将到来的威胁。
Scientists say it’s like the trees are talking to one another.
科学家称，这就像是树木之间在互相“交流”。
Ecologist Suzanne Simard has called this network the Wood Wide Web.
生态学家苏珊娜·西玛德将这个网络命名为“森林万维网”。
She discovered that parent trees use this network to help their offspring.
她发现，母树会通过这个网络帮助自己的后代。
Speaking to the BBC, she said: “We found that the parent trees would favour those seedlings that were of their own kin versus the strangers” by sending them more nutrients.
在接受BBC采访时，她表示：“我们发现，母树会更偏向于给自己的同类幼苗输送更多养分，而非陌生的幼苗。”
She also found that trees are smart enough to change their behaviour and have managed to adapt and survive in a changing environment.
她还发现，树木十分“聪明”，能够改变自身行为，从而适应不断变化的环境并存活下来。
So it seems trees really are the stars of our natural world, and with around three trillion of them on our planet, it’s time to show them some respect if we want them to flourish.
如此看来，树木确实是自然界中的“明星”。地球上大约有3万亿棵树，若想让它们茁壮成长，我们是时候给予它们应有的尊重了。